## Nathalia Serrano

Email me: nathaliaserranoa@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathalia-serrano-924631114/

Call me: 647 299 1468

Address: 121 Acorn Place, Mississauga, ON.

# **Software Developer**

## **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Software developer with a legal background, transitioning from the legal sector to the technology industry, with 4 years of experience in negotiation, risk management, project structuring, decision-making and problem-solving, and 2 years of practical experience in programming. I enjoy collaborating with interdisciplinary teams to achieve common goals in a corporate environment, and I am looking forward to applying my skills in the tech industry.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** JavaScript (DOM), **Frameworks:** React.js, Angular, Node.js, Vue.js,

TypeScript, Python, Java, C#.

**Front-end Development:** HTML5, CSS3, SCSS. **API and Database:** MongoDB, SQL, REST.

Microsoft Office Suite: Excel, Word, Outlook, Power Design: Procreate, Photoshop, Illustrator.

Point. **Other tools:** Wordpress, GitHub, Visio, Draw.io.

**PORTFOLIO:** https://nathaliaserranoanaya.github.io/Portfolio/

LANGUAGES: Native Spanish and English speaker.

#### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

**CENTENNIAL COLLEGE | SOFTWARE ENGINEERING TECHNICIAN** | Toronto, ON | August 2022 – December 2023 Relevant Courses: Web Interface Design, Client-Side Web Development, Java Programming, Web Application Development, Software Systems Design, Software Testing and Quality Assurance, Introduction to Database Concepts and Advanced Database Concepts.

GPA: 3.8 / 4.5

**LOS ANDES UNIVERSITY | BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN LAW** | Bogota, Colombia | January 2013 – December 2017 Relevant Courses: Commercial and Business Law, Consumer Law, Arbitration, Mergers and Acquisitions.

**GPA: 4.2 / 5.0** 

LINKEDIN LEARNING | JAVASCRIPT PRACTICE: EVENTS | ONLINE CERTIFIED COURSE | March 2024

**UDEMY | THE COMPLETE 2024 SOFTWARE TESTING BOOTCAMP | ONLINE CERTIFIED COURSE | February 2024** 

**UDEMY | 100 DAYS OF CODE: THE COMPLETE PYTHON PRO BOOTCAMP | ONLINE CERTIFIED COURSE** | February 2024

PLATZI | JAVASCRIPT PRACTICAL COURSE | ONLINE CERTIFIED COURSE | July 2022

PLATZI | JAVASCRIPT COURSE | ONLINE CERTIFIED COURSE | June 2022

PLATZI | PROGRAMMING COURSE | ONLINE CERTIFIED COURSE | June 2022

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### CINE COLOMBIA - LAWYER; Bogotá (Colombia) November 2018 - July 2022

Cine Colombia is the most important entertainment company in Colombia and one of the best in customer service and technology in Latin America, focused on the distribution and exhibition of films.

- Negotiated and drafted SaaS agreements and proposals in collaboration with the Information Technology department, understanding the product's technical aspects, to ensure compliance with pertinent regulations, mitigate legal risks, and facilitate successful project execution.
- Researched and analyzed regulations related to intellectual property, commercial law, consumer law, and personal data to analyze their impact on the company's operations, translating legal considerations into actionable insights for decision-makers across departments.
- Coordinated the execution of IT, construction, and marketing projects to ensure seamless integration of legal considerations, to prevent potential legal issues that could delay project progress.
- Documented project specifications and stages to provide a roadmap for a successful execution within the contract, ensuring clarity among all project stakeholders' expectations.
- Provided strategic guidance to the customer service department, analyzing complex client complaints, identifying potential legal risks, developing tailored responses and legal strategies to address client concerns effectively, enhancing the company's reputation and customer satisfaction while minimizing legal exposure.
- Significantly reduced the risk of liability and fines through collaboration with the marketing team in structuring advertising campaigns to ensure legal compliance with consumer regulations.
- Facilitated effective collaboration between the company and external legal partners, by actively participating in project-related discussions, to address legal challenges more effectively, align legal strategies with the company's objectives, and enhance trust and reliability.

## SANABRIA GOMEZ LAW FIRM - JUNIOR LAWYER; Bogotá (Colombia) March 2018 - November 2018

- Drafted and reviewed insurance contracts and other legal documents to ensure clarity, accuracy, and legal compliance, and protect the interests of the clients, minimize ambiguities, and establish clear terms and obligations for all parties involved.
- Performed the review of policies and contracts to prepare legal defense in litigation related to the civil liability.
- Conducted research and analysis on insurance laws, regulations, and relevant case law to ensure a thorough understanding and compliance within the claims handling process.
- Planned and executed legal defense strategies for civil liability cases, demonstrating a strategic approach within the legal context.
- Maintained records for all correspondence and documents related to contracts, contributing to efficient project tracking and documentation.

## LOS ANDES UNIVERSITY - TEACHER'S ASSISTANT; Bogotá (Colombia), July 2015 - June 2016

- Enhanced lesson preparation efficiency by collaborating with the lead teacher in organizing materials and setting up equipment.
- Promoted student engagement and achievement by facilitating personalized and small group assistance to support individual student objectives.